<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-12-30T16:53:21+01:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/feed.xml</id><author><name>AgroClim project members</name></author><entry><title type="html">AgroClim-Huaraz at IMD2020</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/12/30/InternMountainDay.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AgroClim-Huaraz at IMD2020" /><published>2020-12-30T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-30T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/12/30/InternMountainDay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/12/30/InternMountainDay.html">&lt;p&gt;On December 11th I was invited to celebrate International Mountain Day and speak on behalf of the project. Together with other PhD students we discussed both professionally but also personally how mountains matter to us and consequently how our research related to our personal understanding of the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was recorded and can be seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J8AYXHHcrTo&quot;&gt;on youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storytelling format presentations of PhD researchers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;@min45:00 Anaïs Zimmer from University of Texas presents first results from Coordillera Blanca Grazing Experiment with Llamas!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hopefully we can all meet physically &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uibk.ac.at/congress/imc2022&quot;&gt;@IMC2022&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/IMD2020/IMD_screenshot.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/IMD2020/IMD_screenshot.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lorenz Haenchen</name></author><summary type="html">On December 11th I was invited to celebrate International Mountain Day and speak on behalf of the project. Together with other PhD students we discussed both professionally but also personally how mountains matter to us and consequently how our research related to our personal understanding of the topic. The event was recorded and can be seen on youtube. Some Highlights: Storytelling format presentations of PhD researchers @min45:00 Anaïs Zimmer from University of Texas presents first results from Coordillera Blanca Grazing Experiment with Llamas! hopefully we can all meet physically @IMC2022!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two AgroClim-Huaraz contributions at EGU2020</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/05/05/EGU2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two AgroClim-Huaraz contributions at EGU2020" /><published>2020-05-05T02:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T02:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/05/05/EGU2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/05/05/EGU2020.html">&lt;p&gt;Our project is well represented at the EGU session about
&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2020/displays/36767&quot;&gt;Recent progress in understanding the hydro-climate system of the Andes: Physical processes and resources for Andean populations&lt;/a&gt;,
to be “chatted” on Tuesday 05 May, 14:00-15:45.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorenz will present first results from field observations with the EC station
and the EcoBot (&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2020/EGU2020-17630.html&quot;&gt;link to abstract and presentation&lt;/a&gt;),
and I will present new results about the relationship of rainfall and convection
in the Rio Santa Basin to large-scale circulation factors
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2020/EGU2020-19981.html&quot;&gt;link to abstract and presentation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward for exiting discussions this afternoon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/egu2020/pigs.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/egu2020/pigs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Pig family in Chinchay.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cornelia Klein</name></author><summary type="html">Our project is well represented at the EGU session about Recent progress in understanding the hydro-climate system of the Andes: Physical processes and resources for Andean populations, to be “chatted” on Tuesday 05 May, 14:00-15:45.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Master topic about remote sensing of plant phenology in the Rio Santa basin</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/03/04/ma-topic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Master topic about remote sensing of plant phenology in the Rio Santa basin" /><published>2020-03-04T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/03/04/ma-topic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/03/04/ma-topic.html">&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a motivated student to join our team and work on a topic
combining remote sensing, ecology and meteorology. You’ll find a
full description &lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ma/Ausschreibung_MSc_Arbeit_RS_Peru.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (PDF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your will have the opportunity to join a dynamic &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt;
to work on a very relevant topic, so apply!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that only students of the University of Innsbruck will be considered.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Georg Wohlfahrt</name></author><summary type="html">We are seeking a motivated student to join our team and work on a topic combining remote sensing, ecology and meteorology. You’ll find a full description here (PDF).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A new member in our team</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/12/01/new-member.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A new member in our team" /><published>2019-12-01T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/12/01/new-member</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/12/01/new-member.html">&lt;p&gt;On December 1st, our team was joined by research scientist
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ceh.ac.uk/staff/cornelia-klein&quot;&gt;Cornelia Klein&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portraits/cokl_klein.jpg&quot; width=&quot;17%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; hspace=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
After a PhD in climate modeling obtained at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imk-ifu.kit.edu/&quot;&gt;Karlsruhe Institure of Technology&lt;/a&gt;
in 2016, Conni was hired as a research associate in land-atmosphere interactions
at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ceh.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;UK Centre for Ecology &amp;amp; Hydrology&lt;/a&gt;. She brings a
strong expertise in atmospheric modeling, convective processes, land-atmoshpere
interactions and tropical climatology. Welcome Conni!!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">On December 1st, our team was joined by research scientist Cornelia Klein.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Field work in Huaraz 2019</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/27/field-work-fabi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Field work in Huaraz 2019" /><published>2019-09-27T02:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-09-27T02:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/27/field-work-fabi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/27/field-work-fabi">&lt;p&gt;In September 2019 a team of three scientists from the AgroClim-Huaraz project
traveled to Peru for the first and most important field work of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/team.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/team.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Georg, Fabien and Lorenz ready to go.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our main objectives was to install an eddy-covariance station on the
field of our partner and friend Hector, farmer in Llupa. We also wanted to
get acquainted with the region and our local partners, as well as preparing the
in-situ measurement campaigns of our PhD student Lorenz, who will spend
several months on site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was quite nervous before the trip, because of many uncertainties regarding
the location of the station and whether or not it would be sustainable to
let it run for such a long period. It turned out that my fears were unjustified,
and the campaign was a tremendous success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will read more about our work there in the upcoming months. In the mean
time, here are a few impressions from the trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/ec_build.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/ec_build_s.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Setting-up the eddy-covariance station.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/aws_llupa.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/aws_llupa_s.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;The “regular” agroclimatic station at Llupa.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/hobo.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/hobo_s.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;A precipitation gauge in the Cordillera Negra.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">In September 2019 a team of three scientists from the AgroClim-Huaraz project traveled to Peru for the first and most important field work of the project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AgroClim-Huaraz at IMC2019</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/10/imc2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AgroClim-Huaraz at IMC2019" /><published>2019-09-10T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-09-10T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/10/imc2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/10/imc2019.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uibk.ac.at/congress/imc2019/index.html.en&quot;&gt;International Mountain Conference&lt;/a&gt;
took place in Innsbruck from September 08 to 12. Our project was very
well represented, with two posters from our group! The first poster was
presented by our Master Student Cornelia Zauner in the fantastic outdoor poster exhibition
of the IMC:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;What are &amp;quot;Puspa&amp;quot; rains? 🌦️ Although very important for farmers in the Cordillera Blanca in Peru, they are not well documented. Here is Cornelia describing them at the outdoor poster session at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/IMC?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#IMC&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Innsbruck?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Innsbruck&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/4LLLPNioJh&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/4LLLPNioJh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Fabien Maussion (@FabClimate) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FabClimate/status/1171543007948132353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 10, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another more general poster, I presented the goals of our project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/imc2019/poster_imc_2019.pdf&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/imc2019/poster_imc_thumbnail.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Click on the image to download a PDF of the poster.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great conference, and the perfect way for us to meet many scientists
working in the region!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">The International Mountain Conference took place in Innsbruck from September 08 to 12. Our project was very well represented, with two posters from our group! The first poster was presented by our Master Student Cornelia Zauner in the fantastic outdoor poster exhibition of the IMC:</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Kick-off meeting 2019</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/blog/kick-off-workshop" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kick-off meeting 2019" /><published>2019-06-09T20:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-06-09T20:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/blog/kick-off-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/blog/kick-off-workshop">&lt;p&gt;The “AgroClim Huaraz Kick-Off Meeting” took place in Innsbruck last week! For
two days (05th and 06th of June 2019), the project members and collaborators
met in a friendly atmosphere. We heard scientific presentations from the
participants and had important discussions about the
upcoming field work and intensive observation period in September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were very lucky to welcome our Peruvian colleagues Alejo Cochachín Rapre
and Rolando Cruz Encarnación (Autoridad Nacional de Agua) for the week.
Fortunately, the weather was very good (almost &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; good maybe?) and allowed us
to have a wonderful workshop dinner at the Umbrüggler Alm, high up above the
city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/kickoff/20190605_Workshop.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/kickoff/20190605_Workshop_s.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;From left to right: Wolfgang Gurgiser, Pierluigi Calanca, Peter Albrecht,
 Alejo Cochachín Rapre, Fabien Maussion, Rolando Cruz Encarnación, Georg Wohlfahrt,
 Cornelia Zauner, Lorenz Hänchen.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">The “AgroClim Huaraz Kick-Off Meeting” took place in Innsbruck last week! For two days (05th and 06th of June 2019), the project members and collaborators met in a friendly atmosphere. We heard scientific presentations from the participants and had important discussions about the upcoming field work and intensive observation period in September.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Can we model Puspa?</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/09/01/modeling-puspa" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can we model Puspa?" /><published>2018-09-01T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-09-01T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/09/01/modeling-puspa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/09/01/modeling-puspa">&lt;h4 id=&quot;puspa&quot;&gt;Puspa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;described as light rainfall or drizzle events that wetten the soil towards the beginning of the new agricultural year at the end of the dry season in August &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.earth-syst-dynam.net/7/499/2016/esd-7-499-2016.html&quot;&gt;Gurgiser et al. 2016&lt;/a&gt; - important for traditional farming since long as deducible from the existence of an own (Quechua) term for these precipitation events&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;not well known from a scientific viewpoint due to missing local experiences (of the scientists) and missing observations with high enough resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As data availability has increased in recent years and luckily, we could observe an event classified as Puspa by our local partners on August 17th (hitting also the area of our newly installed weather station), we are curious to learn more about such events, especially if atmospheric models are able to reproduce them in a realistic way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;myvideo&quot;&gt;
   &lt;video style=&quot;display:block; width:100%; height:auto;&quot; autoplay=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;loop&quot;&gt;
       &lt;source src=&quot;/video/PuspaTimelapse17082018.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
       &lt;source src=&quot;/video/PuspaTimelapse17082018.ogv&quot; type=&quot;video/ogg&quot; /&gt;
       &lt;source src=&quot;/video/PuspaTimelapse17082018.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Images of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://agroclim-huaraz.info/live&quot;&gt;automatic camera&lt;/a&gt; in Huaraz captured on August 17th 2018 from 0800-1830 (10min capture interval). &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the eastern slopes above Huaraz, the event was characterized by slow but continuous cloud development from around 1000 on. Precipitation around Nevado Churup started at 1310 and the area with the presumably highest precipitation rates (as visible from the webcam) was surprisingly stable until 1600. In between this period, some showers also hit the surroundings of Nevado Churup and our weather station in Llupa measured ~2mm of total precipitation. Around 1700, another, more wide-spread precipitation event started with weak rainfall (&amp;lt;0.5mm) also hitting the city of Huaraz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within upcoming research activities we hope to have the chance to thoroughly investigate this and other Puspa events to know whether present day atmospheric models can reproduce these events and if yes, to analyze potential trends in the frequency of Puspa in the Huaraz region in the last decades.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wolfgang Gurgiser</name></author><summary type="html">Puspa described as light rainfall or drizzle events that wetten the soil towards the beginning of the new agricultural year at the end of the dry season in August Gurgiser et al. 2016 - important for traditional farming since long as deducible from the existence of an own (Quechua) term for these precipitation events not well known from a scientific viewpoint due to missing local experiences (of the scientists) and missing observations with high enough resolution</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Student Project 2018</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/08/18/student-field-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student Project 2018" /><published>2018-08-18T20:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T20:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/08/18/student-field-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/08/18/student-field-work.html">&lt;p&gt;In the frame of a joint lecture of the Universities of Hamburg and Innsbruck, 20 students have visited farmers and fields in the Huaraz region in order to setup a new weather station directly at a field-site, check the Hobo precipitation gauges along the &lt;a href=&quot;/region&quot;&gt;“Huaraz transsect”&lt;/a&gt;, investigate soil properties at all &lt;a href=&quot;/region&quot;&gt;measurement sites&lt;/a&gt;, and interview farmers at those sites about their farming methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aws-agroclim-huaraz&quot;&gt;AWS Agroclim Huaraz&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The automatic weather station (AWS) has been installed in Llupa at a field owned by our local partner &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;Hector Oropeza&lt;/a&gt; at 3724 m a.s.l. The AWS records half hourly values of temperature, humidity, radiation (short-/longwave in and out), precipitation and soil moisture at 15, 35 and 60 cm depth. Wind speed and direction will be available as soon as a defect sensor (broken at arrival) can be replaced. Additionally, a simple automatic camera monitors plant growth close to the station. All data are automatically transfered to servers of the University of Innsbruck and current data are available &lt;a href=&quot;/live&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (sometimes data are missing due to missing network coverage).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/AWSAgroClimHuaraz.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/AWSAgroClimHuaraz.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Automatic weather station in Llupa (&lt;a href=&quot;/live&quot;&gt;see data&lt;/a&gt;). New cultivation season will start soon.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;check-of-precipitation-gauges&quot;&gt;Check of precipitation gauges&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 5 Hobo precipitation gauges installed in 2016 were visited, tested and maintained. It turned out that one sensor had a blocked tipping-bucket and another sensor was not measuring because of a loose cable. Fortunately these problems only were present since the last data reading end of July and could be solved. Nevertheless, very simple tests with 20ml of water inserted at each Hobo yield to too many tips at two field sites. Thus, further tests need to be conduced by our local partner &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;Rolando Cruz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/Raingauge.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/Raingauge.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rain gauge at arrival - maintenance required ;-).&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;soil-sampling&quot;&gt;Soil sampling&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As water infiltration rates and storage capacity are a function of soil properties and also other soil features influence plant growth, soil profiles were conduced at all measurement sites. In the field, students analysed e.g. soil type, grain size or rooting depth. They also measured PH values and soil moisture. Furthermore soil samples were collected to be analysed in the laboratory for basic soil
physical properties and available nutrients. When all results are available, we aim to publish them on this webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/SoilSampling.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/SoilSampling.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Students analyzing soil parameters.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interviews-with-farmers&quot;&gt;Interviews with farmers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get an idea which crops are grown on the investigated fields and which methods are used e.g. concerning crop rotation or soil treatments, students interviewed the farmers owning the fields. Prepared questions were used as a guideline to conduce in-depth interviews. To reduce misunderstandings arising from different language and cultural backgrounds, Rolando Cruz moderated the interviews. The statements are now analyzed together with experts and we also aim to publish a summary of these results here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/Interview.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/Interview.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Students conducing interviews with field owners.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;final-remarks&quot;&gt;Final remarks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are very thankful to &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;Aljeo Cochachín and Rolando Cruz as well as Hector Oropeza&lt;/a&gt; who made this very diverse student project possible! We also thank all involved “campesinos” for their trust and willingness to share information with “gringos”. Overall, thanks to our highly motivated students, this lecture will serve as a useful step to facilitate further research activities. Furthermore, teaching and doing research merged during this activity which hopefully yields useful experiences and further opportunities (thesis building on the investigations) for the involved students. We (Martina Neuburger, Wolfgang Gurgiser) in our role as supervisors and curious researchers are thankful for the students’ hard work and enthusiasm!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/Students.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/studentproject/Students.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Students on their way to the study sites in the Cordillera Negra.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wolfgang Gurgiser</name></author><summary type="html">In the frame of a joint lecture of the Universities of Hamburg and Innsbruck, 20 students have visited farmers and fields in the Huaraz region in order to setup a new weather station directly at a field-site, check the Hobo precipitation gauges along the “Huaraz transsect”, investigate soil properties at all measurement sites, and interview farmers at those sites about their farming methods.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Precipitation patterns in the Huaraz Region</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/08/12/proposal-material.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Precipitation patterns in the Huaraz Region" /><published>2018-08-12T15:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-12T15:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/08/12/proposal-material</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2018/08/12/proposal-material.html">&lt;p&gt;In the process of proposal writing we had to remove a few analyzes that, although
interesting, didn’t make it to the final proposal for reasons of space. Since
I like them a lot, I thought I would share them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first graphic shows a map of the annual rainfall (mm yr-1) averaged for the
period 1998-2009. These are precipitation &lt;em&gt;estimates&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. not directly
measured but inferred from satellite data. The climatologies are provided at
~5km resolution by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geog.ucsb.edu/~bodo/TRMM/&quot;&gt;Bookhagen &amp;amp; Strecker (2008)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/material-proposal/trmm_prcp.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/material-proposal/trmm_prcp.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Precipitation in the Huaraz Region as seen by TRMM. Graphic: F. Maussion.
TRMM data: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geog.ucsb.edu/~bodo/TRMM/&quot;&gt;Bookhagen &amp;amp; Strecker (2008)&lt;/a&gt;.
Glacier outlines: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glims.org/RGI/&quot;&gt;RGI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This graphic tells us a lot. First, it shows the very large &lt;strong&gt;gradient of
precipitation&lt;/strong&gt; between the wet amazonian basin (&amp;gt; 3000 mm precipitation per year)
and the very dry Pacific coast (&amp;lt; 50 mm per year). Then, it demonstrates the
&lt;strong&gt;strong influence of orography on the precipitation patterns&lt;/strong&gt;, with high mountain
ridges receiving more precipitation than the low lying valleys. This is a well
known process, but the exact patterns and physical mechanisms vary from one
mountain range to another. Finding out what’s going on in our region in
particular will be one of the goals of our research project. Finally, one
can see that there is also a gradient along our transect: the Cordillera Negra
(“black”, i.e. no snow or glaciers) in the west appears dryer than the
Cordillera Blanca (“white”) in the east. &lt;strong&gt;This is confirmed by our
&lt;a href=&quot;/live&quot;&gt;preliminary observations&lt;/a&gt; along the transect&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second graphic shows a map of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pearson_correlation_coefficient&quot;&gt;temporal correlation (r)&lt;/a&gt;
of each grid point’s monthly precipitation timeseries with the Huaraz grid point timeseries as reference.
The data, obtained from the TRMM V7 gridded precipitation data at ~27km resolution
is coarser than above but has a temporal resolution of 1 month and covers the
period 1998-2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/material-proposal/trmm_ano.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/material-proposal/trmm_ano.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Precipitation temporal variability as seen by TRMM. Graphic: F. Maussion.
TRMM data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmm.nasa.gov/data-access/downloads/trmm&quot;&gt;NASA&lt;/a&gt;.
Glacier outlines: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glims.org/RGI/&quot;&gt;RGI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A high value indicates that this location’s monthly precipitation varies
similarly to the reference location, here on the west of Huaraz. A striking
feature of this map is the very &lt;strong&gt;low correlation between the Cordillera Negra
and Blanca precipitation&lt;/strong&gt;, in particular the higher, northern part.
Along the transect, the correlation also switches from high to low values,
which is indicating that certain wet spells or droughts might happen on one
side of the valley but not on others on certain years. &lt;strong&gt;This has yet to be
confirmed (or not!) by our observations&lt;/strong&gt;, which cover only two seasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these data are very valuable, they are of coarse resolution and have large
uncertainties: &lt;strong&gt;in our project, we will produce a new high-resolution precipitation
and climate dataset to fill these gaps in knowledge and data availability&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">In the process of proposal writing we had to remove a few analyzes that, although interesting, didn’t make it to the final proposal for reasons of space. Since I like them a lot, I thought I would share them here.</summary></entry></feed>