<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2021-08-19T09:44:23+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/feed.xml</id><author><name>AgroClim project members</name></author><entry><title type="html">Lorenz’s first project paper is in review!</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2021/07/19/esdd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lorenz’s first project paper is in review!" /><published>2021-07-19T02:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-19T02:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2021/07/19/esdd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2021/07/19/esdd.html">&lt;p&gt;The first paper of Lorenz’s PhD is now out for review in the open access and open discussion journal Earth System Dynamics! You can read the manuscript &lt;a href=&quot;https://esd.copernicus.org/preprints/esd-2021-60/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this study, we use vegetation indices (mostly: NDVI) to see if they can tell us something about local agricultural practices and, most importantly, about climate variability in the region. Started as a “fallback” project, at the moment where everything related to field work was falling apart because of COVID, this study turned out to be very interesting and a perfect fit for the project. We are hoping for constructive reviews! More about the study will be written here when it is (hopefully) published!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/egu2021/paper_fig.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/egu2021/paper_fig.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;A figure from the study - isn’t it beautiful?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">The first paper of Lorenz’s PhD is now out for review in the open access and open discussion journal Earth System Dynamics! You can read the manuscript here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AgroClim-Huaraz contribution at EGU2021</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2021/04/30/EGU2021.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AgroClim-Huaraz contribution at EGU2021" /><published>2021-04-30T02:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-30T02:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2021/04/30/EGU2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2021/04/30/EGU2021.html">&lt;p&gt;If you are participating at the virtual EGU conference this year, come talk to us in Session CL2.8 
“&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU21/session/40780&quot;&gt;Phenology and seasonality in climate change&lt;/a&gt;”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will present the results of the study I am currently working on, utilizing remote sensing retrievals of vegetation indices to infer 
information about precipitation variability in the Rio Santa (&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU21/EGU21-8330.html&quot;&gt;link to abstract and presentation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward for exiting discussions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/egu2021/paper_fig.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/egu2021/paper_fig.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;A figure from the study - isn’t it beautiful?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lorenz Hänchen</name></author><summary type="html">If you are participating at the virtual EGU conference this year, come talk to us in Session CL2.8 “Phenology and seasonality in climate change”!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AgroClim-Huaraz at IMD2020</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/12/30/InternMountainDay.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AgroClim-Huaraz at IMD2020" /><published>2020-12-30T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-30T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/12/30/InternMountainDay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/12/30/InternMountainDay.html">&lt;p&gt;On December 11th I was invited to celebrate International Mountain Day and speak on behalf of the project. Together with other PhD students we discussed both professionally but also personally how mountains matter to us and consequently how our research related to our personal understanding of the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was recorded and can be seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J8AYXHHcrTo&quot;&gt;on youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storytelling format presentations of PhD researchers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;@min45:00 Anaïs Zimmer from University of Texas presents first results from Coordillera Blanca Grazing Experiment with Llamas!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hopefully we can all meet physically &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uibk.ac.at/congress/imc2022&quot;&gt;@IMC2022&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/IMD2020/IMD_screenshot.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/IMD2020/IMD_screenshot.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lorenz Haenchen</name></author><summary type="html">On December 11th I was invited to celebrate International Mountain Day and speak on behalf of the project. Together with other PhD students we discussed both professionally but also personally how mountains matter to us and consequently how our research related to our personal understanding of the topic. The event was recorded and can be seen on youtube. Some Highlights: Storytelling format presentations of PhD researchers @min45:00 Anaïs Zimmer from University of Texas presents first results from Coordillera Blanca Grazing Experiment with Llamas! hopefully we can all meet physically @IMC2022!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet an Ecology-PhD student</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/07/28/meet-lorenz.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet an Ecology-PhD student" /><published>2020-07-28T02:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-28T02:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/07/28/meet-lorenz</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/07/28/meet-lorenz.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.uibk.ac.at/images/900x-auto/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/images/fieldwork1.webp&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www2.uibk.ac.at/images/900x-auto/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/images/fieldwork1.webp&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; Eddy Covariance station on a potato field at the Cordillera Blanca (Credit: Lorenz Hänchen)  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2019, I joined the interdisciplinary team of &lt;a href=&quot;http://agroclim-huaraz.info/&quot;&gt;AgroClim Huaraz&lt;/a&gt; and became a member of the Biometeorology working group at the Institute of Ecology as a PhD student. I am lucky to have the opportunity to both work in the field and in the office. Due to the variety of tasks in our project I am acquiring many new skills ranging from data analytics, improving my Spanish in communication with Peruvian locals, gaining some basic electronic skills, while maintaining measurement stations and many many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.uibk.ac.at/images/900x-auto/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/images/peruvian-andes_x.webp&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www2.uibk.ac.at/images/900x-auto/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/images/peruvian-andes_x.webp&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; Peruvian Andes Peruvian Andes (Credit: W. Gurgiser)  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climate in the semi-arid Peruvian Andes is very different from what we are used to here in the Alps. It is characterized by a strong seasonality in precipitation, the majority occurring between October and May. Many people who live in the mountains rely on rain-fed agriculture for their livelihoods and these farmers report increasing challenges for crop production due to climate change. There is a general lack in observation data (e.g. by automatic weather stations) in the region and to date the available meteorological data does not match the perception of the local farmers. Our goal in the project is to close this knowledge gap regarding both water demand and water availability to enable the development of effective adaptation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.uibk.ac.at/images/350x-auto/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/images/eco-bot.webp&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www2.uibk.ac.at/images/350x-auto/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/images/eco-bot.webp&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; EcoBot mobile measurement device (Credit: R. Cruz Encarnación)  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly, I am identifying how various crops in rain-fed agriculture differ in terms of energy balance and especially water-use (i.e. evapotranspiration) along a precipitation transect ranging from the glaciated Coordillera Blanca (relatively high annual precipitation) to the unglaciated Coordillera Negra (relatively lower annual precipitation). To measure this, we set up an Eddy Covariance station on a potato field at the Coordillera Blanca in Sep. 2019, take regular biomass samples and use the EcoBot mobile measurement device to measure more crops and plots along the transect. Due to the current COVID-19 crisis we lost some data and our Peruvian partners could not continue the measurements we started last year. But I hope, we can continue our measurements in the near-future, of course depending on the development of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I am working with remote sensing data to understand phenological changes over time (since 2000) and how they correlate with reanalysis data of precipitation to understand whether amounts or the seasonality of precipitation have changed in the phenological cycle of agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.uibk.ac.at/images/200x-auto/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/images/fieldwork2.webp&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www2.uibk.ac.at/images/200x-auto/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/images/fieldwork2.webp&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt; Fieldwork (Credit: R. Cruz Encarnación)  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future, I aim to use our novel field data to calibrate a popular crop model (AquaCrop). First, it will be used on plot-scale and later on regional scale by integrating remote sensing data, iterative parameter estimations and high-resolution climate data on which my colleagues at the ACINN are currently working. With this model-ensemble we will be able to estimate the statistical likelihood of potential threats to successful agriculture. In this context I am also interested whether past (and likely future) changes in precipitation have affected (or are likely to affect) the yield of the crops in the study area.  By extrapolating potential trends of threats into the near-future, an agro-climatic risk assessment of certain agricultural management practices will be an additional result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very happy to have such an interesting job with many different tasks and learning opportunities. I hope, that my work can contribute to progress in the scientific community on the one hand and to climate change adaptation strategies on the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lorenz Hänchen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reposted from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uibk.ac.at/ecology/meet-an-ecology/2020/meet-an-ecology-phd-student-lorenz-haenchen.html&quot;&gt;Insitute for Ecology website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lorenz Hänchen</name></author><summary type="html">Eddy Covariance station on a potato field at the Cordillera Blanca (Credit: Lorenz Hänchen)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AgroClim-Huaraz at Conectate A+</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/07/08/Conectate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AgroClim-Huaraz at Conectate A+" /><published>2020-07-08T02:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T02:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/07/08/Conectate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/07/08/Conectate.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloc.condesan.org/online-conference-on-climate-change-health-and-mountain-ecosystems-and-their-governance-in-support-of-sustainable-development-in-the-tropical-andes-central-america-region-andes-july-7/&quot;&gt;Conectate A+&lt;/a&gt; conference on Climate Change, Health, and Mountain Ecosystems and their Governance in Support of Sustainable Development in the Tropical Andes – Central America Region (Andes+) was a great way to meet with fellow researchers in the Andes regions. Thanks a lot to the organizers of this great conference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maussion, F., Klein, C., Hänchen, L., Wohlfahrt, G., Gurgiser, W., Calanca, P., Cochachín Rapre, A., Cruz Encarnación, R., and Quiñonez Collas, F.: AgroClim Huaraz: water availability and water demand of small-scale farmers in the Rio Santa basin (&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/conectate/Conectate_slides_AgroClim_Maussion.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-file-pdf-o&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; slides&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">The Conectate A+ conference on Climate Change, Health, and Mountain Ecosystems and their Governance in Support of Sustainable Development in the Tropical Andes – Central America Region (Andes+) was a great way to meet with fellow researchers in the Andes regions. Thanks a lot to the organizers of this great conference!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two AgroClim-Huaraz contributions at EGU2020</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/05/05/EGU2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two AgroClim-Huaraz contributions at EGU2020" /><published>2020-05-05T02:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T02:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/05/05/EGU2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/05/05/EGU2020.html">&lt;p&gt;Our project is well represented at the EGU session about
&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2020/displays/36767&quot;&gt;Recent progress in understanding the hydro-climate system of the Andes: Physical processes and resources for Andean populations&lt;/a&gt;,
to be “chatted” on Tuesday 05 May, 14:00-15:45.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorenz will present first results from field observations with the EC station
and the EcoBot (&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2020/EGU2020-17630.html&quot;&gt;link to abstract and presentation&lt;/a&gt;),
and I will present new results about the relationship of rainfall and convection
in the Rio Santa Basin to large-scale circulation factors
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2020/EGU2020-19981.html&quot;&gt;link to abstract and presentation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward for exiting discussions this afternoon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/egu2020/pigs.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/egu2020/pigs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Pig family in Chinchay.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cornelia Klein</name></author><summary type="html">Our project is well represented at the EGU session about Recent progress in understanding the hydro-climate system of the Andes: Physical processes and resources for Andean populations, to be “chatted” on Tuesday 05 May, 14:00-15:45.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Master topic about remote sensing of plant phenology in the Rio Santa basin</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/03/04/ma-topic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Master topic about remote sensing of plant phenology in the Rio Santa basin" /><published>2020-03-04T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-04T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/03/04/ma-topic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2020/03/04/ma-topic.html">&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a motivated student to join our team and work on a topic
combining remote sensing, ecology and meteorology. You’ll find a
full description &lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ma/Ausschreibung_MSc_Arbeit_RS_Peru.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (PDF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your will have the opportunity to join a dynamic &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt;
to work on a very relevant topic, so apply!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that only students of the University of Innsbruck will be considered.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Georg Wohlfahrt</name></author><summary type="html">We are seeking a motivated student to join our team and work on a topic combining remote sensing, ecology and meteorology. You’ll find a full description here (PDF).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A new member in our team</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/12/01/new-member.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A new member in our team" /><published>2019-12-01T01:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T01:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/12/01/new-member</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/12/01/new-member.html">&lt;p&gt;On December 1st, our team was joined by research scientist
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ceh.ac.uk/staff/cornelia-klein&quot;&gt;Cornelia Klein&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portraits/cokl_klein.jpg&quot; width=&quot;17%&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; hspace=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
After a PhD in climate modeling obtained at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imk-ifu.kit.edu/&quot;&gt;Karlsruhe Institure of Technology&lt;/a&gt;
in 2016, Conni was hired as a research associate in land-atmosphere interactions
at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ceh.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;UK Centre for Ecology &amp;amp; Hydrology&lt;/a&gt;. She brings a
strong expertise in atmospheric modeling, convective processes, land-atmoshpere
interactions and tropical climatology. Welcome Conni!!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">On December 1st, our team was joined by research scientist Cornelia Klein.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Field work in Huaraz 2019</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/27/field-work-fabi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Field work in Huaraz 2019" /><published>2019-09-27T02:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-09-27T02:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/27/field-work-fabi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/27/field-work-fabi">&lt;p&gt;In September 2019 a team of three scientists from the AgroClim-Huaraz project
traveled to Peru for the first and most important field work of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/team.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/team.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Georg, Fabien and Lorenz ready to go.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our main objectives was to install an eddy-covariance station on the
field of our partner and friend Hector, farmer in Llupa. We also wanted to
get acquainted with the region and our local partners, as well as preparing the
in-situ measurement campaigns of our PhD student Lorenz, who will spend
several months on site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was quite nervous before the trip, because of many uncertainties regarding
the location of the station and whether or not it would be sustainable to
let it run for such a long period. It turned out that my fears were unjustified,
and the campaign was a tremendous success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will read more about our work there in the upcoming months. In the mean
time, here are a few impressions from the trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/ec_build.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/ec_build_s.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Setting-up the eddy-covariance station.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/aws_llupa.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/aws_llupa_s.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;The “regular” agroclimatic station at Llupa.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/hobo.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/field_work_fabi/hobo_s.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;A precipitation gauge in the Cordillera Negra.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">In September 2019 a team of three scientists from the AgroClim-Huaraz project traveled to Peru for the first and most important field work of the project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AgroClim-Huaraz at IMC2019</title><link href="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/10/imc2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AgroClim-Huaraz at IMC2019" /><published>2019-09-10T14:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-09-10T14:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/10/imc2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://agroclim-huaraz.info/2019/09/10/imc2019.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uibk.ac.at/congress/imc2019/index.html.en&quot;&gt;International Mountain Conference&lt;/a&gt;
took place in Innsbruck from September 08 to 12. Our project was very
well represented, with two posters from our group! The first poster was
presented by our Master Student Cornelia Zauner in the fantastic outdoor poster exhibition
of the IMC:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;What are &amp;quot;Puspa&amp;quot; rains? 🌦️ Although very important for farmers in the Cordillera Blanca in Peru, they are not well documented. Here is Cornelia describing them at the outdoor poster session at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/IMC?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#IMC&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Innsbruck?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#Innsbruck&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/4LLLPNioJh&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/4LLLPNioJh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Fabien Maussion (@FabClimate) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FabClimate/status/1171543007948132353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;September 10, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another more general poster, I presented the goals of our project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/imc2019/poster_imc_2019.pdf&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/imc2019/poster_imc_thumbnail.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;small&gt; &lt;em&gt;Click on the image to download a PDF of the poster.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great conference, and the perfect way for us to meet many scientists
working in the region!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fabien Maussion</name></author><summary type="html">The International Mountain Conference took place in Innsbruck from September 08 to 12. Our project was very well represented, with two posters from our group! The first poster was presented by our Master Student Cornelia Zauner in the fantastic outdoor poster exhibition of the IMC:</summary></entry></feed>